// backend/data/quizData.js
const quizData = [
  {
    company: "tcs",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the full form of TCS?",
        options: [
          "Tata Consulting Services",
          "Tata Corporate Services",
          "Tech Computer Solutions",
          "Tata Computer Services",
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Tata Consulting Services",
        type: "objective",
        difficulty: "easy",
      },
      {
        question: "Where is the headquarters of TCS?",
        options: ["Mumbai", "New York", "London", "Bangalore"],
        correctAnswer: "Mumbai",
        type: "objective",
        difficulty: "medium",
      },
      {
        question: "In which year was TCS founded?",
        options: ["1968", "1975", "1980", "1990"],
        correctAnswer: "1968",
        type: "objective",
        difficulty: "easy",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which programming language is primarily used in TCS projects?",
        options: ["Java", "Python", "C#", "Ruby"],
        correctAnswer: "Java",
        type: "objective",
        difficulty: "medium",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the flagship product of TCS?",
        options: ["TCS BaNCS", "TCS iON", "TCS Quartz", "TCS DCC"],
        correctAnswer: "TCS BaNCS",
        type: "objective",
        difficulty: "hard",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which of the following countries has the largest number of TCS employees?",
        options: ["India", "USA", "UK", "Australia"],
        correctAnswer: "India",
        type: "objective",
        difficulty: "medium",
      },
      {
        question: "Which programming methodology is widely adopted by TCS?",
        options: ["Agile", "Waterfall", "V-Model", "RAD"],
        correctAnswer: "Agile",
        type: "objective",
        difficulty: "medium",
      },
      {
        question: "Which of the following is a key service offered by TCS?",
        options: [
          "Cloud Services",
          "Mobile Application Development",
          "Digital Marketing",
          "Graphic Design",
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Cloud Services",
        type: "objective",
        difficulty: "medium",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    company: "wipro",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Who is the founder of Wipro?",
        options: [
          "Azim Premji",
          "Narayan Murthy",
          "Ratan Tata",
          "Vikram Sarabhai",
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Azim Premji",
        type: "objective",
        difficulty: "easy",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which programming language is used most frequently in Wipro’s projects?",
        options: ["Java", "Python", "C", "Ruby"],
        correctAnswer: "Java",
        type: "objective",
        difficulty: "medium",
      },
      {
        question: "When was Wipro founded?",
        options: ["1945", "1950", "1975", "1982"],
        correctAnswer: "1945",
        type: "objective",
        difficulty: "easy",
      },
      {
        question: "Which of the following is a key business area for Wipro?",
        options: [
          "Healthcare IT",
          "Agriculture",
          "Food Processing",
          "Aerospace",
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Healthcare IT",
        type: "objective",
        difficulty: "medium",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which programming language is Wipro’s Digital Operations & Platforms division focused on?",
        options: ["JavaScript", "Java", "Python", "Ruby"],
        correctAnswer: "Java",
        type: "objective",
        difficulty: "medium",
      },
      {
        question: "Which of these is a notable partnership of Wipro?",
        options: ["Google Cloud", "Amazon AWS", "Microsoft Azure", "IBM Cloud"],
        correctAnswer: "Google Cloud",
        type: "objective",
        difficulty: "medium",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the name of Wipro’s corporate social responsibility initiative?",
        options: [
          "Wipro Cares",
          "Wipro Green",
          "Wipro Cares Plus",
          "Wipro Foundation",
        ],
        correctAnswer: "Wipro Cares",
        type: "objective",
        difficulty: "easy",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which major IT company acquired Wipro’s Global IT Consulting Business?",
        options: ["IBM", "Accenture", "Cognizant", "Capgemini"],
        correctAnswer: "Accenture",
        type: "objective",
        difficulty: "hard",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which programming language is used for automation testing at Wipro?",
        options: ["Selenium", "JavaScript", "Python", "Ruby"],
        correctAnswer: "Selenium",
        type: "objective",
        difficulty: "medium",
      },
    ],
  },
];

export default quizData;
